

PERSONAL PROFILE

A BSc in Computer Science with 5+ years of experience in developing and releasing iOS apps across a variety of industries. Seeking to leverage the problem–solving, teamwork and attention–to–detail skills in order to deliver world–class products.

SKILLS

- Software Development
- Mobile Application Development
- · iOS Development
- Swift Programming Language
- UIKit
- SwiftUI
- Xcode
- Git
- GitFlow
- Teamwork

LANGUAGES

- Brazilian Portuguese (Native Proficiency)
- English (Professional Working Proficiency – IELTS Academic 2022 Grade 7 – CEFR C1)
- German (Elementary Proficiency)
- Spanish (Elementary Proficiency)

AWARDS

- Hackathon Winner Economiza Alagoas Category (2017)
- Gold Medal in Paraiba
 Olympiads in Informatics –
 Advanced Junior Category
 (2013)

IOS DEVELOPER

RUBENS PESSOA

(HE/HIM)

GET IN CONTACT

rubenspbf@gmail.com rubenspessoa.github.io/ linkedin.com/in/rubenspbf/ +43 (677) 6304-1761 Eckertstraße 30C/02 Graz 8020 Austria

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

iTranslate GmbH, Austria | Jun. 2021 - Now

- Contributed to the company's overall product development using UIKit and SwiftUI.
- Improved iOS, WatchOS apps' and App Extensions' codebases by fixing bugs and refactoring them opportunistically.
- Endorsed code sharing by maintaining and improving the company's proprietary libraries as well as included third-party libraries via CocoaPods and SPM (Swift Package Manager).
- Implemented natively the client-side of REST APIs that communicated with the backend via HTTP or WebSocket connections using URLSession.
- Researched newly released technologies at WWDC and engineered proofof-concepts that were later included into the products' roadmaps.
- Used SCRUM as the main agile methodology. Took part in daily, retro, sprint planning, refinement and estimation meetings.
- Applied the GitFlow workflow on Git throughout the repositories in the Github platform. Reviewed and shared knowledge on Pull Requests.
- Key Achievement: Implemented the main screen's redesign for the iTranslate's iOS app. After one month of wide-spread adoption, we have a rate of 99,05% crash-free users according to Firebase's Crashlytics.

Parkside Informationstechnologie GmbH, Austria | Feb. 2019 - May 2021

- Participated in client projects from their product's conception until its release on App Store.
- Contributed to the development of iOS Apps for the Banking and Health Industries using UIKit and SwiftUI, alongside with third-party libraries such as CoreStore, Apollo Client, Moya, KingFisher and Lottie.
- Contributed to the development of a Backend-for-Frontend (BFF) application using NestJS and GraphQL for a client in the Banking industry.
- Contributed to the development of a Progressive Web Application (PWA)
 using React and Redux for a client in the Hospitality Industry.

CloudTaxi, Brazil | Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2018 | iOS Developer Ilhasoft Tecnologia da Inf., Brazil | Nov. 2017 - Apr 2018 | iOS Developer Ilhasoft Tecnologia da Inf., Brazil | Apr. 2017 - Oct 2017 | iOS Internship

EDUCATION HISTORY

UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DE ALAGOAS

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Nov. 2018

Red-White-Red Plus Card Holder with free access to the Austrian Labor Market.